<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natural Language Processing | </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/tags/natural-language-processing/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/~ddm/tags/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Natural Language Processing</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/tags/natural-language-processing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Benchmark for Automatic Essay Scoring in Portuguese</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/publication/silveira-2024-propor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/publication/silveira-2024-propor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Good, Bad and Ugly Arguments Generated by ChatGPT: a New Dataset, its Methodology and Associated Tasks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/publication/rocha-2023-epia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/publication/rocha-2023-epia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ENEM Challenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/project/enem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/~ddm/project/enem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is widely accepted that university entrance exams require human-level
intelligence to be satisfactorily solved. In particular, such exams
require skills such as text and image understanding, informational retrieval,
commonsense reasoning, and mathematical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, university entrance exams constitute a good test for real Artificial Intelligence techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 
 is an advanced High-School level exam widely applied every year by the Brazilian government to students that wish to undertake a University degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;ENEM Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; consists in designing an autonomous system that matches the performance of a human students on the exam. The overall goal is to foster and evaluate the development of Artificial Intelligence techniques that have good performance on complex cognitive tasks, not particularly designed for AI systems. In addition, this challenge aims to promote and give more visiblity to the development of NLP tools for Brazilian Portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The informal and witty aim of the challenge is to get a digital student to be accepted at a main Brazilian university&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dataset&#34;&gt;Dataset&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ENEM exam consists of the writing of an essay and an objective part containing 180 multiple choice questions. The questions are divided into four groups of 45 questions each, namely, Humanities, Languages, Sciences and Mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dataset contains only the textual part of objective part, segmented in questions. Every question is divided into 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;header&lt;/em&gt;, contianing background knwoledge in the form of an image, text or table is given;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;statement&lt;/em&gt;, containing the text of the question;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;answers&lt;/em&gt;, split into five fields, each containing the text of a candidate-answer (A,B,C,D,E), along with an additional tag informing the correct answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, every question is annotated with the following tags:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt;: the question number in that assessment;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;image&lt;/code&gt;: does it has an accompanying image in the exam?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;EK&lt;/code&gt;: does it require knowledge not given in the header?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;TC&lt;/code&gt;: does it require textual understanding of the header?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;IC&lt;/code&gt;: does it require understanding of the associated image?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DS&lt;/code&gt;: does it require complex inference or domain specific knowledge?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;MR&lt;/code&gt;: does it requires transforming instructions in natural language into mathematical formula?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CE&lt;/code&gt;: does it require treating chemical elements especially?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the challenge uses an XML version of questions taken from the exams between 2009 and 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more in-depth description of the dataset is found 
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 776kb zip archive containing the XML file can be downloaded 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you design a new solution, please 
 reporting accuracy, reference (if any) and information as below. Here is a list of current solutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Paper&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Accuracy&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Note&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;citation&#34;&gt;Citation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use this dataset, please cite the following work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    @InProceedings{ ENEM-Challenge,
            author = {Silveira, Igor Cataneo and Mau\&#39;a, Denis Deratani},
            booktitle = {Proceedings of the 6th Brazilian Conference on Intelligent Systems},
            series = {BRACIS},
            title = {University Entrance Exam as a Guiding Test for Artificial Intelligence},
            pages = {426--431},
            year = {2017}
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
